First Name: Last Name: Pronouns:
Nandhini Anand She/Her
Contact No.: Known Languages: Email ID:

9632745308 English, Tamil, Hindi, Kannada nandhini.jeyahar@gmail.com

Alternate Email ID:

anand.jeyahar@gmail.com

Summary

At the core a Generalist with around 16+ years of Hands-on experience in Technology. Experience distribution is around 7 years in Python web backends, about 3 years in Baan ERP and the rest in the DS/ML/AI space using Python. Data experience includes roles in data engineering, data warehouse building, data visualization, data dashboard design and building predictive models ranging from traditional regression, and random-forest, to neural networks with CNN, GANs etc.

Work Experience

Sr	Company	Designation	Duration
1	The Math Company	Senior Data Scientist(Decisions)	Dec. 2022 - Oct. 2023
2	VIT Infotech	Senior Technical Architect	Mar. 2022 - Oct. 2022
3	Mouritech Pvt. Ltd	Senior Technical Architect	Mar. 2021 - Sep. 2021
4	Smartek21 Pvt. Ltd.	Senior Technical Specialist	Oct. 2020 - Feb. 2021
5	Trishula Adv.Comp. and Electronics Pvt. Ltd	Senior Data Scientist	Apr. 2019 - Jul. 2020
6	Kaliber Labs Pvt. Ltd	Senior Data Scientist	Apr. 2017 - Mar. 2019
7	Greytip HR Solutions	Senior Data Scientist	Aug. 2015 - Mar. 2017

Responsibilities Overview

The Math Company (Senior Data Scientist)

- Built a dashboard and searchable UX interface for the internal employees and their skills, project allocation and other details.
- As part of the Faculty Development Program(FDP) went and delivered 5-day training for faculties (to teach data science) at SRM and SASTRA Universities.

VIT Infotech (Senior Tech Architect)

- · Code Review, Pull-requests project that involved creating faust and Kafka stream processing
- Integrate the on-site team's code to create the various python module that process the input GPS and pressure info and finally produce an altitude estimate. Guide a couple of Junior Engineers in terms of coding practices, setting up their environment, debugging etc.
- · Add faust-streaming app-based filtering microservices for adding Indoor guessing models
- Fix and deploy a complex decision-maker app to decide whether to accept or reject a new calibration (of altitude) attempt from a mobile device

Mouritech (Senior Technical Architect)

- Contribute to the search engine that parses multiple document formats(pdf, PPT, docx) indexes them and provides
 a search interface.
- Contribute exception module and validation module to the invoice pdf parsing and creation of SAP invoices application on Azure function App platform Guide, plan and lead a team of 5 engineers to set proper environments for development, demo, and production using docker

Adroitent ITES (Senior Data Scientist)

• Worked on null value analysis and data validity for car GPS data for a driving pattern and insurance type correlation challenge.

Trishula Adv. Comp. & Electronics (Senior Technical Architect)

- Establish good code conventions and educate the team on the same via the code review process.
- Worked as a contractor for a leading auto manufacturer helping them with visualizing the vehicle GPS and other data specific to automobiles
- Assembled a lightweight data pipeline framework for collecting sensor and device status data from various distributed IOT devices.
- Built a data set simulator and model for the creation of a carbon tax incentive and the impact on tax revenues and market demand for green energy.

Kaliber Labs Pvt. Ltd (Senior Data Scientist)

- Assembled a Text analytics pipeline, leveraging STORM, Kafka, Hadoop and NLTK for parsing huge XML docs and identifying named entities in them.
- · Built a pre-sales demo with NN-based models for audio-cleaning tools with a GAN-based NN model.
- Helped with building a speech-to-text pipeline (using Kaldi) on top of the previous model. (After comparing APIs from AZURE, Gcloud, and IBM Watson for the same).
- Deployed Video analytics(voice and vision-based NN models) for predicting (and visualizing) emotions during an interview.
- Helped the Pre-sales team, with writing proposals for RFPs, making them more technically sound and sensible, and also helping them with the costing.
- Built a kidney stone size estimation tool for the online assistance of kidney stone lithotripsy procedures.(using paper space cloud)

Greytip HR Solutions (Senior Data Scientist)

- Deployed dashboards with metrics and trend visualizations for monitoring attrition/access and economic health metrics (Monthly Recurring Revenue, Customer Lifetime Value, Customer Acquisition Cost etc..).
- Built a team of Pythonistas for maintaining, enhancing, and bug-fixing the data pipeline, ETL warehousing, and dashboard applications mentioned above. Modelled and Demonstrated a couple of predictive models to predict upsells and account loss probability.
- Designed, guided and helped set up end-to-end data warehouse (from distributed data sources), data pipeline, data-sanity checks, data dashboards, and data modelling notebooks.
- Built random-forest models to predict customer attrition and reduced attrition rates, by designing a proactive customer engagement process. Demonstrated a couple of predictive models to predict upsells and account loss probability as POC.
- Implemented a Reservoir sampling mechanism(with SQL triggers & random) and a generic SQL generator for the same.
- Built a open source tool called data-science-tools to help with the EDA step by giving easy data visualizations and playbooks for analytical thinking

Qualification

Sr	Qualification	Board/University	Passing Year
1	M.Sc.	Allahabad University	2009

Sr	Qualification	Board/University	Passing Year
2	B.E.	Madurai Kamaraj University	2004
3	12th	Tamil Nadu State Board	2000
4	10th	Tamil Nadu State Board	1998

Skills: AWS, GCS, AZURE, DigitalOcean

Python, C, R, rustic, asm in descending order of skill. IDE/Environments Linux, vim, bash shell, jupyter. MySQL, Postgres, Redis, MongoDB, Cassandra

Hadoop, STORM, Kafka, Airflow, etc. bokeh, seaborn, plotnine, d3.js.

Area(s) of Interest: Data Science

Karnataka

ΑI

Machine Learning

Analytics

Achievement at different roles before Aug. 2015:

Reduced annotation time by half, by automating parts of the video

annotation task.

Helped scale from 1 to 2 Mn users in the backend to handle

responsiveness demands (including migrating from Mongodb + AWS to

Redis + GCS).

Built a Cohort-analysis tool for checking and verifying weekly retention rates and helped decide on features to build based on that tool. Improved user engagement with a ranking system for posts, based on TF-IDF score, recency, rarity, and length(of text) in the post. Increased User engagement, by building a chatbot to play word

games.

Current Location

State:

City/Town: Bangalore